metroexpresslanes.net 2014-03-31

# Metro ExpressLanes

### Privacy Policy

###### 

  * Collection of Personal Information
  * Customer Rights and Choices
  * Use of Personal Information
  * Sharing of Personal Information
  * Retaining of Personal Information
  * Changes to Privacy Statement

Metro recognizes and respects the importance of maintaining your privacy. Metro will only use the information you provide for customer communication and to facilitate transactions. The Metro ExpressLanes Privacy Policy is effective as of January 23, 2012. 

##### Collection of Personal Information

Metro will only collect personal information voluntarily provided by customers to facilitate the establishment and management of ExpressLanes account registration or other purposes listed herein. When customers register for an account, Metro will ask all individuals to provide basic personal information needed to manage account activity. The basic information may include, but is not limited to, name, home or work address, telephone number, email address, license plate number, credit/debit card number, expiration date, and other billing information. 

Metro may require customers to provide certain personal information in order to complete a specific transaction online. The information is required in order to provide the customer with specific services. The customer may choose not to provide information. However, if a customer chooses not to provide information, Metro will not be able to complete the transaction or provide services. The customer will have to complete their transaction either in person or by mail. 

We will also ask customers for demographic information, including but not limited to, zip code and income level. Providing this demographic information will be optional and not a requirement to establish an active account. 

When customers access their account online, they will login using their user name and password. Metro will implement appropriate measures to help safeguard login information and ensure there is a secure procedure for generating and changing passwords. Customers may review and make changes to their Personally Identifiable Information by logging into their account at www.metroexpresslanes.net or call 511 or 877-224-6511 (if outside LA, Orange, Ventura Counties). 

##### Customer Rights and Choices

Customers and visitors have the right to restrict the sharing of personal information to Metro and/or its third party service provider. Unless the customer asks Metro not to, Metro and/or our third party service provider may contact the customer via email or phone in the future to inform them of such things as new ExpressLanes products or services, promotions or changes to this Privacy Statement. Customers may make the privacy choice at any time and will remain unchanged until the customer chooses otherwise. Customers may exercise that choice by contacting Metro and/or our third party service provider by phone, email or online. 

##### Use of Personal Information

Metro collects and uses personal information to enhance our operation and improve its web site and offered services. These uses may include providing customers with more effective customer service and performing research and analysis aimed at improving ExpressLanes products, services and technologies. The personal information is also used to provide customers with reminder notices, billing information, technical information and announcements. 

##### Sharing of Personal Information

Metro may disclose personal information to third-party service providers to facilitate in the course of doing business (i.e., DMV, law enforcement, municipal courts or collection agencies); otherwise it will not be disclosed, except by law or ordered by a court. Metro will not sell, trade, distribute or disclose the customer's personal information unless disclosed in this Privacy Statement or we notify the customer and have received their consent. 

Metro may provide aggregate information about our customers' use of Metro ExpressLanes services and online website information to our funding partners, advertisers and agency partners. Such aggregate information will not contain any personally identifiable information. 

Metro may employ other companies and individuals as a third party service provider to perform functions on Metro's behalf as allowed by law. Third party service providers have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but personal information may not be used for other purposes. Metro may disclose personal information to our service providers in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringement, piracy or other activity that may expose us to liability. 

##### Retaining of Personal Information

The information collected through the Metro website is retained by the Metro and its third party service provider in accordance with applicable records retention and disposition requirements of Metro and California laws. 

##### Changes to Privacy Statement

Metro will occasionally update this privacy statement to reflect changes in our services and customer feedback. If there are material changes to this statement or in how Metro will use personal information, we will notify the customer either by prominently posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change or by directly sending the customer a notification. Customers are encouraged to periodically review this statement to be informed of how Metro will protect customer information.
